Contact

E-Mail: kj.garza@gmail.com Github: <u>github.com/kjgarza</u>

Observable:

<u>observablehq.com/akjgarza</u>

LinkedIn:

linkedin.com/in/kjgarza

Published work

Garza, K., & Buys, M. (2021). *A Brave New PID: DMP-IDs*doi.org/10.5438/J22A-5D79

de Jong, M. & Garza, K. (2019). Project FREYA: Connecting Open Knowledge in the European Open Science Cloud (EOSC) doi.org/10.5281/ZENODO.3517852

Garza, K. (2013). Individual Motivations Change Activity in Online Scientific Communities. figshare.

doi.org/10.6084/M9.FIGSHARE.830
404

Skills

redis, ElasticSearch, Solr, MySQL. GraphQL, REST.

Kibana, Logstash.

AWS (ECS, RDS, EC2, S3, CloudFront, Route53, Lambda, SQS), Terraform, Docker, Github Actions, Jenkins, DataDog, Sentry.

R, Python, Ruby, TypeScript, Javascript, PHP, Gherkin, CSS. react, Vue, ember, Rails, Jupyter, django, flask, NextJs.

KANBAN, Aqile.

Google Analytics, Tag Manager, ProductBoard, BDD, TDD.

Design Sprints, A/B experiments, Workshop design, User Journeys JTBD, User Stories, Personas, Stakeholder Mappings, Double Diamond, WireFraming.

Figma, Miro.

DOIs, ORCIDs, RORs, Bibliometrics.

Kristian Garza

High-performing Application Developer and Web Product Lead with a passion for agile methodologies the and seven years of experience impacting positive organizational outcomes through detailed UX research and sound software architecture design in the Open Science community domain.

Experience

PRODUCT DESIGN MANAGER

DataCite 2021 - today

PRODUCT DESIGNER

DataCite 2020 - 2021

APPLICATION DEVELOPER

DataCite 2016-2020

- Established the DesignOps
 processes that allowed DataCite to
 research, design, and ship
 features and products on time.
- Performed DefinionOfDone and Code reviews for all product releases.
- Led the feature design and information architecture of <u>DataCite's main web platform</u>.
- Performed both idea and solution validations for complex web applications with expert stakeholders.
- Architected and implemented a Usage Metrics processing pipeline (inc. <u>REST API, queueing, display</u>) that is currently used by hundreds of organizations worldwide.
- Refactor DataCite's Search service from <u>Java Implementation to a Ruby</u> <u>app with Rails</u>.
- Developed a <u>React SPA using</u>
 <u>Typescript with GraphQL backend</u>.
- Implemented data visualization dashboards using D3, ggplot, Vega, and Vega-lite.

Education

PHD

The University of Manchester 2012-2016

MSC

University College London 2007-2008 PhD in Computer Science

- <u>Investigated factors that affect</u> the <u>publication of research data</u> in digital scholarly platforms.
 - Performed statistical data analysis using R for A/B experiments

<u>Masters in Spacecraft Technology</u> <u>And Satellite Communications</u>

 Defined design improvements of electron detectors.

https://kjgarza.github.io/